ANDREW D. KHU, MBA

3601 SW River Pkwy., #417. Portland, OR 97239

andrewkhu@hotmail.com Phone: 503-567-4250

PROFILE

Experienced professional with variety of experience from 5+ years of legal support to 8+ years of project management. Looking to re-enter the work force after a hiatus. Excels at building and managing relationships, building teams, and working in a multi-cultural office. Strong organizational, analytical, presentation, and communication skills.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration 2001

Atkinson Graduate School of Business, Willamette University Salem, Oregon

Concentrations: Finance and MIS

Bachelor of Arts 1993

Bennington College Bennington, Vermont

Concentration: Liberal Arts / Architecture and Ceramics

Community College of the Air Force 1984-1985

Plattsburgh AFB, NY Nellis AFB, NV

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Professional Arms

Portland, Oregon 2007 - 2011

Entrepreneur and Product Designer

- Developed and produced a working prototype of the Mk5 multi-caliber rifle system
- Successfully obtained the "Mk5" trademark from the USPTO
- Successfully obtained first round financing with angel investors
- Marketed proof of concept product at trade shows such as SHOT and IACP
- Worked with law enforcement agencies with the Mk5's design and user requirements
- Managed change controls for product development and improvement
- Research and developed other products that are patent pending

B&R Machine

Portland, Oregon 2006 - 2007 Machinist

- Operated manual metal cutting machines: Lathes, Mills, Electric Discharge Machines, Boring, Surface Grinders and Drill Presses
- Quality Assurance technician. Used precise testing equipment to verify accuracy of internal and outsourced parts
- Learned purchasing and supply line on the job. Used prints to order raw materials and purchased tools for jobs
- Communicated with vendors to insure supply chain is not disrupted
- Learned and became experienced in Solidworks 3D solid modeling software
- Assisted tool maker in setting up machines for operations

Master Systems Inc.

Portland, Oregon

2004 - 2006

Project Management Consultant (PMP certified)

- Planned and managed software development and IT improvement projects
- Established and operated the project management office for several large IT based companies
- Analyzed problem areas with software development through interviews with developers and testers. Defined and communicated problems to stakeholders. Recommended a course of action to remediate problem areas. Developed metrics to track problems and its improvements
- Led cross functional teams of staff, contractors, clients, and vendors
- Managed projects and budgets effectively for client driven objectives

Fry's Electronics

Wilsonville, Oregon

2003 - 2004 (Part Time)

- Computer Repair Technician
 Troubleshot and repaired PCs
- Installed PC components and upgraded PCs.
- Backed up and restored data on customer machine
- Use test equipment for CPU, RAM, monitors, etc

Windermere Investment Associates

Portland, Oregon

2001 - 2002

Manager, Performance Reporting and System Administrator

- Supervised 3 full time financial analysts, 4 full time outsourced analysts and 2 consultants
- Presented and met face to face with high net worth clients
- Managed programmers to develop a financial reporting software package.
- Contributed to the growth model of the company by managing the outsourcing of the reporting department while developing and installing an in-house financial reporting software system

- Managed, tracked and resolve issues from the new reporting software
- Installed, maintained and upgraded servers, intranets and websites
- Setup all work stations with PCs. Installed applications, and logons to servers and emails

Willamette University, Atkinson Graduate School of Business

Salem, Oregon

2000 - 2001

Teaching / Research Assistant

- Taught a 15-week financial economic modeling class to 25 MBA students using MS Excel
- Assisted Professor Dothan with his academic paper by creating futures trading models. Ran computer model simulations with historical and real time commodities trading data. Created and maintained databases in MS Access

Mayer, Brown & Platt

Los Angeles, California 1995 - 1999

Library Assistant

- Researched and compiled public information for litigation and business cases
- · Assisted attorneys and paralegals in finding relevant materials for legal research
- Maintained the library's PCs and database. Troubleshot and upgraded hardware and software as needed.
- Processed invoices and track accounts payable for library's books
- Ordered, labeled, and entered data for books and media into the library's tracking system
- Performed interlibrary loans with public and private libraries

Morgan, Lewis & Bockius

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

1994 - 1995

Paralibrarian

- Provided on-line and traditional research assistance at the library reference desk
- Assisted attorneys and paralegals for online research in specialized legal databases
- Performed daily database backup and maintenance

United States Air Force

Plattsburg AFB, NY and Nellis AFB, NV

1984 - 1987

Electrical Power Production Specialist / Aircraft Arresting Barrier Specialist

- Maintained and repaired aircraft arresting barriers. Fighter and light bomber aircrafts use their tail hooks to safely land when their aircrafts during emergency landing situations
- Maintained and repaired electrical power generators at critical facilities on and off base
- Secret clearance and US citizen
- Discharged honorable